Giancarlo Solano

Peru



gsolanogti@outlook.com



linkedin.com/in/gsolanoqtj

Summary

Hello, let me show you something about myself.

I really enjoy developing software and leading a team.

I have more than 7 years in the technology industry developing projects, new functionalities, bug fixes and support for other developers. And I'm always improving my skills

If you want to know more about my jobs, read my experience below.

Experience



www Tech Lead

Workia Solutions

May 2021 - Feb 2022 (10 months)

- Leading the technical support of the team in Java technologies (SpringBoot Framework), Angular +5, Aws.
- Support in functional / technical definition of requirements, their estimation and breakdown into tasks.
- Direct coordination with the IT Architect and Scrum Master for the management of new technologies and delegation of work.
- Distribution and allocation of load within the development team.
- Ensure the fluidity of development within the team.
- Development of requirements with external suppliers.
- Implement KPI's within the development team.



www. Java Fullstack Dev Senior

Workia Solutions

Feb 2019 - May 2021 (2 years 4 months)

- Leading the technical support of the team in Java technologies (SpringBoot Framework), Angular +5,
- Analysis of requirements, solution proposals and estimation times with Sprint Tickets.
- Intermediate Level in AWS: EC2, ECS, RDS, CloudWatch.
- Development of web services with NestJS.
- Development of web services with Java 8 and SpringBoot with Gradle.
- Use: Netflix libraries(Zuul, Hystrix, Ribbon, Feign), Multitenant, Config Server, OAuth2, Kafka, Redis
- Integration with Camunda BPM, DMN
- Development in databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Neo4j
- Frontend development: Angular >= 5, Bootstrap 3, PrimeNG
- Web Services Test with tools: SoapUI, Insomnia.
- Linux: Command Console
- Version Control Repository: GIT
- Pass to Quality and Production environments with Gitlab-CI/CD.



Extech - Innovation Lab

Aug 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 5 months)

- Managing projects with an external team
- Requirements estimation.
- Definition of requirements architecture.
- Implementation of architecture based on mongo, docker on ec2 aws.
- Development of requirements on .Net, Angular +6.
- Internal Development Delegation.

.Net Fullstack Dev Senior

Extech - Innovation Lab

Mar 2019 - Aug 2019 (6 months)

- Analysis of requirements, solution proposals and estimation times.
- Development of web services with .NET: Web API 2.0, MVC 5, C#, ADO, SAP Connector
- Development in databases: Mssql
- Frontend development: Angular >= 5, Bootstrap 3
- Integration with Firebase
- Version Control Repository: GIT

Java Fullstack Dev Senior

Diners Club Perú

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 (6 months)

- Leading the deliveries of internal requirements of simultaneous projects of a team of 4 people.
- Validation, deployment of the Diners Club Online product and continuous improvements.
- Analysis of requirements, solution proposals and estimation times.
- Migration of Java web applications: JDK 1.5 to JDK 1.8.
- Java application server migration: Jboss 4.2 to Wildfly 10.
- Development of web applications with Java: JEE 6, JEE 7, EJB, JPA, JSF, RichFaces, Hibernate, JDBC.
- Development of web services with Java: JAX-WS, RESTful Jersey, RESTful Spring.
- Development of web services with .NET: Web API 2.0, MVC 5, C#, , Entity Framework, ADO
- Development of web applications with Php
- Development in databases: DB2, Mssql, Mysql, MariaDB
- Development of programs in AS400: RPGLE, CL, SQL
- Frontend development: Html, Pug, Javascript, Angular 2, NodeJS, TypeScript, Css, Scss, Bootstrap 3
- Web Services Test with tools: SoapUI, JMeter.
- Configuration of Application Servers: Wildfly 10 in Linux y Windows, IIS, Apache
- Linux: Command Console, Crontab, Services
- Pass to Quality and Production environments with attached documents.

№ Java Fullstack Dev - Senior

MDP CONSULTING S.A.C

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 8 months)

- Leading the deliveries of internal requirements of simultaneous projects of a team of 4 people.
- Migration of internal projects affected by migration of the banking core to Unibanca.
- Analysis of requirements, solution proposals and estimation times.
- Migration of Java web applications to Core Unibanca.

- Development of web applications with Java: JEE 6, JEE 7, EJB, JPA, JSF, RichFaces, Hibernate, JDBC.
- Development of web services with Java: JAX-WS, RESTful Jersey, RESTful Spring.
- Development of web services with .NET: Web API 2.0, MVC 5, C#, , Entity Framework, ADO
- Development of web applications with Php
- Development in databases: DB2, Mssql, Mysql, MariaDB
- Development of programs in AS400: RPGLE, CL, SQL
- Frontend development: Html, Pug, Javascript, Angular 2, NodeJS, TypeScript, Css, Scss, Bootstrap 3
- Web Services Test with tools: SoapUI, JMeter.
- Configuration of Application Servers: Jboss 4.2 in Linux y Windows, IIS, Apache
- Linux: Command Console, Crontab, Services
- Pass to Quality and Production environments with attached documents

.Net Fullstack Dev - Ssr

SIGCOMT

Jun 2016 - Dec 2016 (7 months)

- Compilation of information and analysis of requirements with the clients internal areas.
- Requirements analysis based on functional documents and time estimation.
- Development of desktop application with .NET: C#, Asp.NET, ADO, MetroFramework
- Version Control Repository: GIT
- Development in databases: Mssql, Mysql, MariaDB
- Authentication using Active Directory
- Passes to Quality and Production environments
- Development of .bat scripts for restart, stop of Apache Server
- Generation of installers for Client-Server
- Development of NPS optimization system with filtering of data generated by internal channels.
- Application development for bulk file upload
- Development with geolocation apis: Google Maps Geocoding API, Yahoo! Maps Web Services Geocoding API and Bing Maps REST Services
- Development of ETL from Oracle to Mssql

Practicante Pre Profesional de Soluciones de Datos

Entel

Jul 2015 - May 2016 (11 months)

- Preparation of daily and weekly reports of sales and churn advances in business solutions and broadband.
- Analysis of the portfolio of business solutions and broadband
- Monitoring of the main accounts at risk of business solutions.
- Training to the accounts that are in the process of recruitment.
- Adaptation of business solutions to the need of the account and your business.
- Development of web applications with .NET: C#, ADO
- Development of web applications with Java
- Development in databases: Mssql
- Mobile development in Java for Android using Eclipse
- Filters and Data exploitation with Excel
- Extraction of data from internal websites using Javascript

Practicante Pre Profesional Analista Programador

Universidad Nacional de Trujillo

Jan 2015 - Jun 2015 (6 months)

- Academic Management System for UNT-PIC12-2013
- RUP documentation for the Quality process
- Process Modeling using Bizagi
- Development of web application with Php
- Frontend development using ExtJs
- Development in databases: Postgresql
- Trainings in RUP, Desserts, Bizagi



Php Fullstack Dev - Jr

CALZADOS ROMINA

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014 (7 months)

- Compilation of requirements with the involved areas.
- Requirements analysis.
- Web development in PHP
- Development in databases: Mysql
- Frontend development: Html, Javascript, ExtJs 3.4, Css
- Development of reports

Education



Universidad Nacional de Trujillo

Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Systems Engineering

2010 - 2015

Leader of Academic Community "Mi Primer Código".

Influencer of Academic Community Microsoft UNT.

Member of Academic Community Isaca Student Group.

Skills

Java • JavaScript • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • C# • Databases • Team Leadership • Full-Stack Development • Apache Kafka • Redis • Microservices